Nandor Tibor Szots

Personal Profile

Self-motivated engineering leader who enjoys mentoring his teams to achieve their full potential. Extensive experience in building, coaching, and motivating teams of engineers to consistently deliver results on aggressive timelines. Also have a proven track record of designing practical solutions to complex problems, while ensuring maintainability and reusability.

Work Experience

Amazon July 2016 - Present

Position: Manager, Software Development III

Leading an Organization responsible for multiple key parts of Amazon's PrimeNow and Fresh businesses.

My teams are responsible for the following technologies:

- Notifications Desktop, Mobile, SMS, and Email event based notifications
- Order Modifications All technologies associated with modifying an order which is already created
- Automated Refunds All technologies associated with Event-Based Automanted Refunds
- Stores Data Model Data Models, Storage and Lookup capabilities of all worldwide stores with low latency and high availability requirements

Created a hiring pipeline, including processes, procedures, tracking and metrics for the San Diego site which successfully hired over 150 engineers in 12 months and increased the population of the site by 9-fold over 3 years. Used the knowledge gained building out the San Diego site to create a recommended best practices guide for other cities to follow which has been implemented by 4 other sites globally to date.

Sony Online Entertainment

January 2013 - July 2016

Position: Technical Director

Projects: EverQuest II, EverQuest Next and EverQuest Landmark

Worked with other technical personnel on developing new company-wide technologies. Helped design and architect key systems for new and existing games.

Built and lead the EverQuest II team as both a technical leader and people manager. Responsible for both key technical decisions as well personnel decisions on EverQuest II. Played an integral role in the hiring processes for the EverQuest Franchise.

Lead teams of C++ and Web Developers in building the in-game marketplace and showcase for display and real-time sale of both player and SOE created items - Landmark Showcase. This feature was designed and brought to market in a record 6 months and accounts for over 50% of the profits of the game.

Designed, architected and lead the team in implementing:

- Backend C++ servers which control the searching of and sale of these items.
- Recommendation system to suggest purchases to users.
- UI for creating player made items, along with UI Artists and Producers to make sure all needs were met.
- Web Based UI through which players can search for and find items to purchase. This UI was the same both in and out of game to ensure a unified code-base which required minimal effort to keep synchronized between the two UIs.
- Daily digest email of products which is personalized based on a users interests.
- Mobile and Desktop shopping UX support.

Sony Online Entertainment

January 2012 - January 2013

Position: Lead Programmer Project: EverQuest II

Lead a team of programmers in developing new features and refreshing, enhancing and giving new purpose to previously used features in the popular EverQuest II MMORPG.

Responsible for architecting new systems, Full Team scheduling, project time estimates, and daily tasking of the EverQuest II code team.

Sony Online Entertainment

January 2006 - January 2012

 ${\it Position:} \ {\rm Senior} \ {\rm Programmer}$

Project: EverQuest II

Implemented the EverQuest II and EverQuest II: Extended marketplace functionality including: all back-end commerce and server-side communications. Transitioned the original implementation of the marketplace into a highly successful Free-to-Play model, while maintaining a non-Free-to-Play service as well.

Responsible for all marketplace improvements, changes and new technology development. Responsible for live-game maintenance, including daily investigation of both client and server crashes by using Linux core dumps and Windows mini-dumps to identify and resolve issues. Responsible for development and deployment of mobile companion app for the the core game.

Designed and implemented a tool for third-party sites to be able to obtain information about in-game characters, items and spells. This system used EDB and X-Path to index XML blob data for fast searching of relevant game data.

Implemented a bayesian filter for all game messages to combat the growing spam problems. The filter has a 99% accuracy rate and blocks on the order of 500,000 messages per day.

Updated and maintained game servers and client in C++/STL. Implemented new game systems and features based on player feedback. Worked with the Test Server community to build a stronger relationship between development and players.

Acted as the game team's point of contact for internationalization across over 4 locales including Russian, French, German, and Japanese. Developed code which allowed for faster identification of strings requiring localization and reduced redundancy in localizing dynamic game data.

Created designer tools for fast indexed searching of over 50 gigabytes of game data. These tools were rapidly developed using GNU/Linux, perl, php, apache and other open source tools.

General Atomics - Lynx Systems

January 2003 - January 2006

Position: Lead Software Engineer

Wrote embedded C, compiled for vxWorks running on various VME boards.

Projects included: View Manager Board which displayed radar imagery in near-real-time using OpenGL; Lynx Ground Control Station: received radar imagery via a high-speed serial (RS422) data link, decompressed, displayed and forwarded images to other systems via Ethernet; Utility applications: allowed for quick and easy loading of code onto radars which consisted of a C back-end running on the radar and a C# user interface running on a PC.

Trouble shot various hardware and software problems in the field as a radar integration specialist. Part of integration team for FireScout, and KingAir. Software integration lead for Predator B.

Software Engineering Lead on SAR/GMTI project.

AudioTalk Inc. / HearMe Inc.

June 1998 - July 2001

Position: Junior Engineer / Operations Engineer

University of California, Santa Cruz December 1998 - December 2002

Position: Student Grader/Lab Assistant/Volunteer Tutor

University of California, Santa Cruz

Position: Residential Computer Coordinator

Education

University of California, Santa Cruz

1998 - 2002

December 1998 - June 2000

B.S. in Computer Science.

Relevant Skills: C, C++, Java, C#, Online Marketplaces, Monetization System Design, OpenGL, Unix¹, Regular Expressions, vxWorks, Tornado, MS Dev Studio, STL, PL/SQL Dev, vi, gmake, cvs, sh, perl, flex, bison, LATEX, assembly language², HTML, Win9x / NT / 2000 / XP / 7, MS-DOS, SQL, Databases³, Perforce, CVS, git, RS-232, RS-422, VME Knowledge.

References

Available upon request.

¹Linux: Debian, RedHat, SuSE, Slackware; Sun: Solaris

²RISC: SPARC, MIPS, and Motorola MC68xx (MC68HC11A8) assembly

³MSDE, Oracle, MySQL, Postgres, EDB, MongoDB